CV Ave Ottens http://ottens.me/CV/

Curriculum Vitae

This CV is also available as a PDF.

Personal Information

Name Ave Ottens

Email ave [at] ottens [dot] me
OpenPGP Key work-in-progress

About Me

Tinkering computer scientist and self-taught programmer. A sharp eye for detail, but I can iterate quickly if needed. I have a solid understanding of computing concepts, and a surprising amount of experience. Good at communication, I thrive in interdisciplinary and diverse environments. I would enjoy a job where I could apply and expand my knowledge of mathematics.

Education

2018 - 2022 BSc Computer Science and Engineering at Eindhoven University of Technology,

Netherlands

• GPA: 7.8/10

- Final project on GPU-accelerated audio simulation in a large team, for a real-world client.
- Elective packages on computer security, AI + data science, sustainable design, and electronics.

2011 - 2017 VWO at Liseo Boneriano, Bonaire, Caribbean Netherlands

- · Graduated best of class.
- Final project on Captcha cracking using artificial neural networks.

Extracurricular Activities

2021 Guest speaker at conference 'Differ(ent) kinds of energy'

 Together with a classmate, we compiled and presented the needs of LGBTQ+ students at the TU/e.

2021 Activist at Rainbow Academy, Nationale Jeugdraad

• Campaigned for higher quality and more accessible healthcare for young LGBTQ+ people, through discussions with government officials.

2018 - 2021 Yearly participant in the Eindhoven Algorithmical Programming Challenge

2020 **Lead developer** at A Place for Now

- A Place for Now is a student-led initiative, pairing homeless (international) students with student hosts that can accommodate them while they search for housing.
- · Recruited and guided new team members.
- We won the Audience Prize at the TU/e Contest 2020.

2019 **1st place** at Wallifornia MusicTech Hackathon

- Used a motion capture device to control digital audio effects with body movements.
- Worked in an interdisciplinary, ad hoc team.

1 of 3 9/20/2022, 9:06 AM

CV Ave Ottens http://ottens.me/CV/

2015 - 2018 Various code projects

- Made a game engine in JavaScript.
- Created a few multiplayer web games.
- Made a web scraper for torrent traffic.
- · Created a Discord bot.

2012 - 2018 **Junior Ranger** at Stinapa Bonaire

- · Had weekly lessons in biology and conservation.
- Contributed on scientific projects on jellyfish and sunscreen.
- Joined debates on climate policy.
- Transplated and cultivated endangered corals.

Teaching Experience

2017 - 2018 Self-employed mathematics tutor

- Taught VWO exam-level mathematics. (Wiskunde B)
- Made schedules with students and studied the learning material intensively.

Work Experience

2017 - 2018 Tour guide at Watertaxi Kantika di Amor

• Entertained and educated tourists about nature on Bonaire.

2017 - 2018 Restaurant staff at Cuba Compagnie Bonaire

- Served food and drinks in one of the busiest restaurants on Bonaire.
- Discovered a vulnerability in the cash register software that allowed unauthorized users to open it.

2016 - 2017 Web developer at SkillsProf

- Along with another student, we developed a new website for our high school.
- Maintained the SkillsProf e-learning platform.

Skills

Soft Skills SCRUM, public speaking, (academic) writing and documentation, literature search

Embedded Systems C, C++, Linux, Assembly, Arduino, Raspberry PI

GPU Programming OpenGL, WebGL, OpenCL

Security Metasploit, Kali Linux, Wireshark

Databases SQL, PostgreSQL, optimalization, Hadoop Data Science Python, Cython, Spark, R, machine learning

Game Development Unity, C#, Blender

Web Development Google Cloud, JavaScript, REST APIs, Node.js, Vue.js, HTML, CSS

Design Photoshop, Figma

Mathematics LaTeX, discrete math, complexity theory, probability and statistics, linear algebra

Software Engineering UML, requirements gathering, unit testing, Java

Other Git, Docker, Ruby, audio engineering, Ableton, automated testing, soldering!

Language Proficiency

DutchFluentEnglishFluentPapiamentuStudent

2 of 3 9/20/2022, 9:06 AM

CV Ave Ottens http://ottens.me/CV/

Hobbies

Thanks for reading this far! I enjoy playing any instrument I can get my hands on. I also hike a lot, and recently I've been writing more poetry.

website made by Ave in pure HTML (/ \bigcirc 7 \bigcirc)/*: \cdot $^{\circ}$ \Leftrightarrow

3 of 3